Guide to the Experiment Station Publications Photographic Collection 1949-1979
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
- Fisheries and Wildlife
  - Stream pollution in Willamette River near Eugene; taken by Bill Reasons, 1959; P132:164 (Box 1)
    Negative 1697E
  - Graduate student Floyd Hutchins feeds young coho in test of growth ability, 1960s; P132:165 (Box 1)
    Negative 00200E
  - OSU researcher Dean Lee Shumway checks fish swimming ability in water of varying oxygen concentration which is pumped through tubes at varying velocity, Summer 1967; P132:166 (Box 1)
    Negative 00196E
  - Carl Bond catching a 12-inch trout, 1960s; P132:167 (Box 1)
    Negative 25E
  - Charles Warren, OSC fisheries biologist, examines artificial stream before production of kraft paper mill wastes at OSC fisheries laboratory; taken by B. Reasons, Sept 1956; P132:168 (Box 1)
    Negative 1435E
  - Arrowtoothed sole or turbot. Proved to be an excellent growth promoter for mink, 1951; P132:169 (Box 1)
    Negative 743E
  - Black Rockfish, proved excellent to use in mink diet as promoter of dark fur color, 1951; P132:170 (Box 1)
    Negative 744E
  - Meadow Mice. See "Oregon's Agricultural Progress" winter 1960 issue, P132:171-P132:172 (Box 1)
    Negative 1700E and 1702E
  - Finding out how moles live is paying off in control of this animal, Summer 1962; P132:173-P132:174 (Box 1)
    Negative 1990E
  - Pheasants; taken by Mason, July 1957; P132:175-P132:176 (Box 1)
    Negative 1548E and 1545E
  - Pheasant cock; taken by Mason, July 1957; P132:177 (Box 1)
    Negative 1547E
- Animal Sciences
  - Experimental mink, 1951; P132:178-P132:181 (Box 1)
    Negative 754E-757E
  - Natural rank mink from OSC fur farm, no date; P132:182 (Box 1)
    Negative 1704E
  - View of OSC sheep on hill pasture, Fall 1955; P132:183 (Box 1)
    Negative 1227
  - Idwal Ralph Jones, dairy scientist, offers new hay wafer to dairy cow in OSC trials comparing the wafer with standard alfalfa pellets; taken by R. Birdsall, Apr 1958; P132:184 (Box 1)
    Negative 1660E
  - Part of Squaw Butte-Harney range herd, no date; P132:185 (Box 1)
    Negative 908E
  - Hereford cattle in Texas; taken by Jack Miller, May 1961; P132:186 (Box 1)
    Negative 1789E
- Home Economics
  - Test patients are on control diets for 30 days to determine vitamin needs for human subjects. From left, (facing camera) Margaret Fincke, Clara Storvick, Nina Morley, and Betty Hawthorne (back to camera); taken by Mason, June 1957; P132:187 (Box 1)
    Negative 1497E
- Food Technology
  - Finding a wide variety of tasteful, wholesome foods at the supermarket, Winter 1969; P132:188 (Box 1)
    Negative 00194E
- Animal Sciences
  - Bob Chestnutt, graduate student, puts arm in clear up to shoulder when removing cud from rumen, 1960s; P132:189 (Box 1)
    Negative 1233E
  - Bob Chestnutt, graduate student, examines cud taken from cow's rumen, 1960's; P132:190 (Box 1)
    Negative 1235E
- Fisheries and Wildlife
  - Oyster larva clinging to glass slide growing as artificial seed at Yaquina Bay, 1960s; P132:191 (Box 1)
    Negative 996E
- Pesticides, Herbicides, and Insecticides
  - Tansy Ragwort infested with cinnabar moth, 1960s; P132:192-P132:193 (Box 1)
    Negative 1330E
  - Burning English rye grass stubble to prevent blind seed disease. E.G. Mason farm, Jefferson, Oregon, Summer 1961; P132:194 (Box 1)
    Negative 1870E
  - Gorse growing on beach near Bandon, 1960s; P132:195-P132:196 (Box 1)
    Negative 1022E-1023E
- Soils
  - Sample of soil erosion in Columbia Basin taken just north of the town of Moro, Mar 1956; P132:197 (Box 1)
    Negative 1240E
  - Erosion on Columbia Basin wheatlands, no date; P132:198 (Box 1)
    Negative 1591E
- Pesticides, Herbicides, and Insecticides
  - Crop dusting of chemical sprays control weeds in seeds and grain, Spring 1963; P132:199 (Box 1)
    Negative 2001E
- Crops and Irrigation
  - Luther Fitch and experimental stand of Lenore flax at Malheur station where it was seeding in mid-March. This is a fall-seeded crop in Willamette Valley; taken by Birdsall, Summer 1963; P132:200 (Box 1)
    Negative 1938E
  - Sprinklers at work in orchard at the Hood River branch experiment station, Summer 1950; P132:201 (Box 1)
    Negative 322E
- Water/Irrigation
  - Natural flooding of meadows in late spring was used by early settlers, Fall 1970; P132:202 (Box 1)
    Negative 00249E
  - View of overhead sprinkling designed for corn irrigation experiments at East farm, no date; P132:203 (Box 1)
    Negative 942E
  - Use of small plot irrigator on sweet corn at vegetable crop farm, Corvallis; taken by Harry Mack, Aug 1957; P132:204 (Box 1)
    Negative 1601E
  - Luther Fitch setting siphon tubes on onion plots at Malheur station; taken by Birdsall, Summer 1963; P132:205 (Box 1)
    Negative 1943E
- Crops
  - Mint under irrigation between Madras and Redmond, no date; P132:206 (Box 1)
    Negative 1360E
  - Harvesting barley at E.G. Mason farm, Jefferson, Oregon; taken by Mason, Aug 1957; P132:207 (Box 1)
    Negative 1549E
  - Augering 40-fold wheat from bin into truck for delivery into Heppner. Frank Wilkinson farm, near Heppner; taken by Mason, Aug 1957; P132:208 (Box 1)
    Negative 1617
  - Alfalfa seed being harvested in Umatilla county; taken by Bill Stephen, Aug 1961; P132:209 (Box 1)
    Negative 1894E
  - Stacking hay loose has proved faster and more economical on the Henry Klages and Sons ranch, Joseph, where feeding is done near the haystack, July 1960; P132:210a (Box 1)
    Negative 1793E
  - Alfalfa and grass hay in windrows ready to be stacked. Henry Klages and Sons ranch, Joseph, July 1960; P132:210b (Box 1)
  - Seed bed preparation with a D-2 Caterpillar and Van Brunt cultivator. Bill Cool farm, Joseph, May 1961; P132:210c (Box 1)
  - Hay is transported by trucks and farmhand to a feed lot. Henry Klages and Sons ranch, Joseph, Mar 1960; P132:211 (Box 1)
    Negative 1795E
  - J. Ritchie Cowan in forage breeding plots at Hyslop farm; taken by Birdsall, 1955; P132:212 (Box 1)
    Negative 1912E
  - Agronomist Rod Frakes examines alfalfa flower being used for breeding; used in Oregon's Agricultural Progress, Fall 1960; P132:213-P132:214 (Box 1)
    Negative 1737E
  - Winter safflower being tested at Pendleton station by Laurn Beutler; taken by R. Birdsall, Summer 1963; P132:215 (Box 1)
    Negative 1933E
  - Charles Rohde (left) and President Jensen examine stripe rust resistant Omar during Pendleton Station 1963 Field Day; taken by R. Birdsall, Summer 1963; P132:216 (Box 1)
    Negative 1921E
- Horticulture
  - Linda Clement, 5, and Charles Ruettgers, 4, of Scio, were among 2000 visitors from throughout the Northwest who visited the 1953 annual Oregon Early Chrysanthemum Show and Field Day at Corvallis, October 3-4; taken by R. Birdsall, Oct 1953; P132:217 (Box 1)
    Negative 804E
  - Dr. David Chilcote, head of straw utilization project, hods cubes of perennial ryegrass straw for experiments, Dec 1970; P132:218 (Box 1)
    Negative 00162E
  - Walt Mellenthin at Lewis Brown farm with dwarf apple plantings, June 1951; P132:219 (Box 1)
    Negative 586E
  - Elmer Hansen, OSC Horticulturist, examines carbon dioxide level as being piped onto polyethylene bags to find out what causes brown core in pears; taken by Mason, Sept 1956; P132:220 (Box 1)
    Negative 1443E
  - Elmer Hansen and lab apparatus which detects amounts of various acids present in stored pears. See story in "Oregon's Agricultural Progress", Spring 1961; P132:221 (Box 1)
    Negative 1752
  - Jesse E. Harmond makes flax movies while his flax tour visitors look on. From left to right: Harmond (at the projector),; Leonard Klein, Agricultural Engineer; Fred Shideler, head of Journalism; F.A. Gilfillan, Dean of Science; Norville R. Gish, assistant experiment station editor; extreme right man unidentified, Aug 1950; P132:222 (Box 1)
    near Mt. Angel.
    [Negative 234E]
  - Henry Harman, OSC Horticulturalist, examines Golden Doyenner pears, on of the tested varieties he thinks adapted for commercial trial; taken by Mason, Mar 1957; P132:223 (Box 1)
    Negative 1505E
  - Vera Jorgenson of Corvallis picking apples; taken by Bill Reasons, July 1957; P132:224 (Box 1)
    Negative 1553E
- Crops
  - Wilson Foote, OSC Agronomist, removes anthers from inbred barleys in preparation for crossing with other lines. Taken at Granger, 1960; P132:225 (Box 1)
    Negative 1009E
  - Mr. Harry August Schoth standing in the original planting of Alta Fescue on the Oregon Agricultural Experiment Station, Corvallis, Oregon, 1960; P132:226 (Box 1)
    Negative 1196E
  - Application of 80 pounds nitrogen fertilizer (actual N) per acre on test plots of Elgin winter wheat at Malheur branch experiment station will yield estimated 60 bushels per acre on plot at left compared to 30 bushels for unfertilized plot at right. Station superintendent Neil Hoffman says recent mild winters have increased interest among local farmers in winter wheat. Year's work load is distributed by seeding in the fall rather than during busy spring season; taken by Birdsall, July 1954; P132:227 (Box 1)
    Negative 820E
  - Ralph Garren counting strawberry leaves taken from plants treated with radioactive Maleic Hydrazide, Nov 1961; P132:228 (Box 1)
    Negative 1844E
  - OSU Horticulturist Harry John Mack examines a test planting of broccoli, 1968; P132:229 (Box 1)
    Negative 00225E
  - Unidentified harvest scene, no date; P132:230 (Box 1)
    Negative 455E
  - Harvesting an unknown crop, no date; P132:231 (Box 1)
    Negative 593E
  - Flax field binder-loader in action near Mt. Angel. Developed by flax research engineers, July 1950; P132:232 (Box 1)
    Negative 287E
  - New push type flax puller which shows promise of substantial savings to the fiber flax industry, no date; P132:233 (Box 1)
    Negative 288E
  - Cuber, on Hyslop farm. Leased for two years for straw utilization project. Machine used to cube ryegrass straw for experiments, Dec 1970; P132:234 (Box 1)
    Negative 00152E
  - View of new OSC greenhouses, no date; P132:235 (Box 1)
    Negative 1134E
  - Visitors viewing the OSC mum farm, 1950s; P132:236 (Box 1)
    Negative 39E
  - Hyslop Farm: Wilson Foote, Al Meyers, Roy Ward looking at Abruzzi rye, 1953; P132:237; 2 b/w prints. (Box 1)
  - Wilson Foote at Hyslop Farm, 1954; P132:238; b/w print (Box 1)
  - Strawberry Pickers Wanted signs used in Strawberries for Tomorrow film about mechanical harvesting of strawberries, circa 1979; P132:239-P132:241; color prints and camera negatives (Box 1)